Total Experience: 3 Year(s) 7 Month(s)

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computer Science]

Notice Period: 2 Months



Software Developer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, IT Project Management, Requirement Gathering, Defect Management, Angular 5, Angular 6,HTML,JSON,HTML,CSS,JavaScript,GIT,Bootstrap,Typescript



Current Designation: Software Developer -Web Application

Development

Current Company: Mobinius Technologies Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, IT Project

Management, Requirement Gathering, Defect Management, Angular 5, Angular

6,HTML,JSON,HTML,CSS,JavaScript,GIT,Bootstrap,Typescript

Verified: Phone Number 1 Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Summary

A goal-oriented professional offering near 3 years of experience in Web Application Development using Angular (5/6/7/8), HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Typescript, Bootstrap & JSON

Working with as Aveva (Schneider Electricals) as Software Developer,

Bengaluru; currently working on "GCS Web"

Worked with as Software Developer with Mobinius, Bengaluru; worked on "Green Cubes"

Worked as Angular Developer with Axtrics, Mohali (Punjab); worked on "Suvidha" Project for ERP portal implementation Gained exposure of gathering & providing process requirements and use cases for business, functional & technical

Proficient in Web Application Development Lifecycle right from requirement analysis, documentation (functional specifications & technical design), coding & testing (preparation of test cases along with implementation) to maintenance of proposed applications

Experience in working with Angular 5/6/7/8 Modules, Services, Templates, Directives, Services & Dependency Injection to create SPA

Work Experience

Mobinius Technologies as Software Developer -Web Application Development Sep 2019 to Till Date

Technical Responsibilities:

Designing, building & maintaining websites using scripting languages, content creation tools, management tools and digital media.

Integrating Restful Api.

Maintaining understanding of current web technologies or programming practices through continuing education, reading, or participation in professional conferences, workshops or groups

Developing & validating test routines & schedules to ensure that test cases mimic external interfaces and addressing all browser & device types

Axtrics Solutions as Angular Developer Jun 2017 to Sep 2019

About Axtrics: Axtrics is a leading Product Development Company which build Products for their Clients. Suvidha is Complete Erp solution which is Built by Axtrics and it has been implemented in over 10 Companies. Suvidha is highly flexible Erp which can be greatly tailored according to Customer needs. Success of Suvidha is attributed to quick implementation and great User experience.

Projects:

Project Title: Suvidha

Period: Since Jul'17 to Sep'19.

Technologies Used:HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Angular 5, Angular 6, Bootstrap, .NET Core, SQL, JS Report. Description: The project is focused on ERP portal implementation to create invoices/ purchase orders, tracking inventory/ inward-outward stock movements & wastage, performing bank reconciliation, recording journal entries, managing list of customers & vendors, viewing all accounts & finance related daily activities, supporting multi-currency transactions, administering payroll function and performing category transactions according to the project. Majorly worked on Sales Module, Production Module, Report Generation Module and Marketing Module

Technical Responsibilities:

Designing, building & maintaining websites using scripting languages, content creation tools, management tools and digital media.?

Integrating Restful Api.?

Maintaining understanding of current web technologies or programming practices through continuing education, reading, or participation in professional conferences, workshops or groups?

Developing & validating test routines & schedules to ensure that test cases mimic external interfaces and addressing all browser & device types?

Providing clear & detailed descriptions of website specifications such as product features, activities, software, communication protocols, programming languages, and operating systems software and hardware? Monitoring security system performance logs to identify problems and notify security specialists when problem occurs Coordinating with teams to resolve conflicts, prioritizing needs, developing content criteria & choosing solutions? Identifying problems uncovered by customer feedback & testing and correcting / referring problems to appropriate personnel for correction?

Evaluating code to ensure the validation, structure and compatibility with browsers, devices or operating systems? Fixing bugs, troubleshooting and resolving any other escalated problems by the clients?

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computer Science) from CMRIT, Bangalore in 2017

IT Skills

| Skill Name | Version | Last Used | Experience | |
|------------------------|------------|-----------|----------------------|--|
| Angular 6 | 6.0 | 2019 | 1 Year(s) 0 Month(s) | |
| TypeScript | | | 2 Year(s) 0 Month(s) | |
| Windows & Linux-Ubuntu | | | | |
| JavaScript | | | 2 Year(s) 0 Month(s) | |
| RxJS | | | 2 Year(s) 0 Month(s) | |
| Angular | 5,6,7,8,10 | 2020 | 3 Year(s) 7 Month(s) | |
| NPM | | | 3 Year(s) 7 Month(s) | |

Languages Known

| Language | Proficiency | Read | Write | Speak |
|----------|-------------|------|-------|-------|
| English | | | | |
| Hindi | | | | |

Projects

Project Title: Suvidha Client: Confidential

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Aug 2017 - Till Date

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: The project is focused on ERP portal implementation to create invoices/ purchase orders, tracking inventory/ inward-outward stock movements & wastage, performing bank reconciliation, recording journal entries, managing list of customers & vendors, viewing all accounts & finance related daily activities, supporting multi-currency transactions, administering payroll function and performing category transactions according to the project

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General

Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No

Employment Status: Full time